# Adrian Martin Senior Full Stack Engineer

• Hialeah, Florida 33015

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/adrian-m-41a8b6259/

**s** live:.cid.e5633f6d5650b892

## **PROFILE**

Self-motivated Full Stack developer with 10 years of experience working on multiple projects. Passionate and hardworking with a penchant for meeting deadlines. Experience includes collaborating in team-driven environments to create high-performance web applications that customers and businesses love.

#### **SKILLS**

## **Back-end Technologies and Frameworks**

NodeJS, ExpressJS, Ruby on Rails, Spring Boot, Laravel, PHP, Java, Python, RESTful API, GraphQL, OAuth, Webpack

## **Content Management System**

Directus, WordPress, Shopify, Strapi, Sanity

## **Version Control Tools**

Git(Github, Gitlab), CVS, SVN, VSS(Visual Source Safe)

## Front-end Languages and frameworks

ReactJS, Angular, AngularJS, VueJS, React Native, NextJS, NuxtJS

#### **Database Management Systems**

MySQL, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, SQL Server

#### **DevOps**

AWS, Azure, Docker, Kubernetes, Jenkins, Ansible

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Jul 2020 - Mar 2023 Raleigh, North Carolina, **United States** 

## **Senior Full Stack Engineer**, Albet ∅

- Built and maintained large-scale applications using ReactJS, Angular, Vue, Node/ExpressJS, Laravel, MySQL, and MongoDB from scratch resulting in a 20% increase in application productivity and a 15% increase in conversion rates.
- Led a team of 5 developers in delivering several high-visibility projects, including a mobile-first redesign of the website and a real-time product customization tool.
- Learn and adopt cutting-edge new technologies into our project: Implement Typescript on server environment by re-writing the whole backend project. Implementing testing case and automation testing workflows using Jest, Mocha, Jasmine, Cypress, etc.
- Extensive interaction with the clients on requirement gathering and estimation on Sprint planning and user stories tracked in Agile methodology with Jira, Trello, etc.

Jul 2017 - Jun 2020 Charlotte, North Carolina, United States

#### Senior Full Stack Engineer, Axim ≥

- Developed and maintained e-commerce & healthcare platform using React, Angular, NodeJS, MySQL, and MongoDB.
- Collaborated with a team of 10 developers to deliver the project on time and within budget, while ensuring high quality and maintainability.
- Implemented advanced features such as real-time streaming, client-side form validation, robust error handling, and logging to improve the stability and reliability of the application.
- Worked in Agile methodologies for incremental development to deliver better applications and used Jira and Git as version control and tracking units.
- Environment: ReactJS, Redux, React Hooks, React Native, Redux-Saga, Thunk, Angular, Vue, JWT, Typescript, Javascript, HTML5/CSS3, Ajax, Bootstrap, Github, Gitlab, Jasmine, MongoDB, SQL, NodeJS, ExpressJS, Agile.

Jul 2013 - Jun 2017 Ankeny, Lowa, **United States** 

### **Software Developer,** Pratum *⊘*

- Designed, Developed an internal management system using HTML, CSS, JSON, Javascript, jQuery, Bootstrap, and Ajax, PHP from scratch.
- Worked closely with our business product owners on an agile team to fully understand requirements, provide feedback, and request clarification as needed.
- Executed the SEO project single handily in Agile. Involved in requirement and analysis with the clients plus developing, enhancing & testing the application using Javascript, CMS tool, TFS, HTML5, and CSS3.
- Integrated MongoDB for lifetime backend database storage across multiple clients and developed sorting algorithms for adding and updating thousands of requests at a time.

• Participated in team meetings with the remote team and corporate clients to understand the needs of a new implementation. Participated in daily team meetings and scrum meetings.

## **EDUCATION**

2008 – 2012 San Francisco, United States Bachelor's degree - Computer Science, San Francisco State University

GPA: 3.7/4.0

## **CERTIFICATES**

- AWS Certified DevOps Engineer Professional
- Free Code Camp Full Stack Development Certification
- Dynamics CRM Application Certification
- Professional in Web Accessibility (PWA)
- Microsoft Certified Solutions Developer (MCSD)
- Microsoft MTA Database Certificate Fundamentals
- Certified Web Developer (CWD)
- Certified Front End Developer (CFED)